Like a fairy tale
It's a sign the story has reached its end
Like a single passage taken from
A journey that was too long
Of the evil that once cast a shadow
Across this land
And the memories of the short journey
With the hero who defeated it
The story ends
And the hero goes to sleep
Leaving this land with
Days of peace and quiet
The passage of time heartlessly
Makes people forget
Even the tracks left behind by his life
Begin to rust
Just the same
Your words and wishes and courage
Are still inside of me
And they live on
We chose the same path
That's all it was supposed to be
Why is it that at some point
I wanted to understand the reason for
The tears that fall down my cheeks
Even now
If I retrace the journey we walked together
Even though you're not there
I know I'll be able to find it
Ms. Frieren is falling asleep.
What?
She's asleep.
Oh, well. I'll carry her.
But Mr. Stark, your axe...
Oh, right.
My hands are free, though.
I'll carry her.
What? Why?
No reason.
In the end, the king only
gave us ten copper coins.
What a cheapskate.
I'm not surprised.
Many heroes have tried and failed
to defeat the Demon King until now.
There's nothing wrong with
earning money to cover expenses
while working toward
defeating the Demon King.
It'll feel like an adventure.
I suppose you're right.
That's the Hero's Sword.
It's a replica.
Back in the day, a merchant who
visited my town gave it to me
for saving him from a monster.
"For the future hero," he said.
Just something you'd say to a kid.
Is that why you became a hero?
No.
There was this annoying brat named
Heiter at the village orphanage.
He said I'd only ever become a fake hero
because all I had was a fake sword.
So I decided I'd prove him wrong
by becoming a real hero.
Someday, I'll acquire the real Hero's Sword
and defeat the Demon King.
But the passage of time is cruel.
The brat who said that to me is now
a fake priest who just drinks all the time.
I'm a real priest.
A dream...
Ms. Frieren, you're finally awake.
I feel like I've seen this sight before.
I must still be dreaming.
If only you were.
I underestimated the mountain weather.
Keep going north. The village
we're heading to is up ahead.
Very well.
Ms. Frieren, can you walk?
No.
I see.
You smell nice.
Sheesh.
You must be tired from carrying
her this whole time, Fern.
I'll take her now.
Perv.
How am I a perv?
The blizzard has mostly settled down.
I thought we'd freeze to death.
There really is a village this
deep in the mountains, huh?
We've been waiting for you, Ms. Frieren.
You're the current village chief?
You're so young.
Yes. I'm the 49th in a long line of chiefs.
Welcome to the Village of the Sword.
There was a destroyed cabin
outside the village.
It's an old hunting cabin.
The lord of the mountains destroyed it.
The lord of the mountains?
Has there always been one of those?
So this is the Village of the Sword.
You know of this place, Mr. Stark?
This village used to protect the Hero's Sword.
The Hero's Sword was said to have been
placed in a sanctuary near this village.
Throughout history, many heroes tried to
pull it from the stone, but it wouldn't budge.
Not until eighty years ago, anyway.
According to the legend, uh...
"The Hero's Sword can only
be pulled from the stone
by the hero who will drive off the great
calamity bent on destroying this world."
Yeah, that's it.
And it was Mr. Himmel who
drew the sword from the stone?
That's right. I thought it was
a pretty famous story.
You hadn't heard it before?
No. Mr. Heiter never mentioned it.
This is it.
So warm.
Anyway, I'm disappointed, Ms. Frieren.
You were supposed to return
half a century later.
I'm a mild-mannered person,
but even I'm pissed off.
At least, that's what my grandmother said.
I told her eighty years would be fine.
The people of this village, who've protected
the Hero's Sword for generations,
can easily defend themselves.
That's true, but we still
need you to fulfill your duty.
What duty?
Monster extermination.
Monsters regularly appear around this village.
The lord of the mountain has been especially
unruly lately. It's been a real problem.
Then I'll start tomorrow.
Better to deal with this
sooner rather than later.
This area is full of monsters,
even though the village is nearby.
Why didn't you hire other
adventurers to exterminate them?
I wish we could, but...
It's because Himmel is the hero.
You weren't kidding.
There sure are a lot of monsters.
They're gathered in front of that cave.
Frieren, is this—
It's the lord.
I see.
No wonder I didn't know who she meant.
It's a new face.
Only eighty years, and you
consider yourself a lord?
Stark, I know you can keep moving.
Can't you treat people better?
Nice work.
Now I've fulfilled my duty.
Frieren, what's the meaning of this?
That's the Hero's Sword.
It's what attracts all the monsters.
A powerful barrier prevents them
from entering the sanctuary,
but even so, they can't suppress
their impulse to destroy it.
The Hero's Sword must truly terrify them.
That's not what I meant.
Right.
Himmel failed to pull
the sword from the stone.
So this hero wasn't the real one either.
Himmel...
There's nothing wrong
with being a fake hero.
I'll defeat the Demon King
and bring peace to the world.
Then it won't matter if I'm fake or not.
Himmel lived up to those words.
Even without that sword, he saved the world.
He was a real hero.
Then why was the truth covered up?
It was probably done by people who
wanted to make Himmel a hero.
No hero needs embarrassing
stories told about them,
like the time they failed to pull
the Hero's Sword from its stone.
Future generations always
romanticize heroes,
to the point that their original
nature eventually disappears.
I always believed you
could do it, Ms. Frieren.
I'm hella grateful.
My grandmother said that as well.
What's up with the words
your grandma left you?
Well, see you in another fifty years.
Don't be late next time.
Once we leave our belongings at the inn,
everyone's free to do what
they want for the evening.
We haven't been to a town in a while.
We can finally cut loose.
Ms. Frieren, what will you do?
Shall we look around the shops together?
I'll pass.
I'd like to relax here at the inn
and read some grimoires.
I see. In that case, I'll go alone.
Oh, right.
Today is Stark's eighteenth birthday.
Why didn't you tell me that beforehand?
I didn't get him anything.
You can buy something for him in town.
I don't know what Mr. Stark wants.
You don't think things through, do you, Fern?
This is your fault, Ms. Frieren.
By the way, what are you giving him?
I've got something special planned.
A potion that only dissolves clothing.
My master told me men enjoy
receiving this kind of gift.
What? Are you curious, Fern?
I told you to return this vulgar
potion when you bought it.
I can't believe you, Ms. Frieren.
That potion was pretty valuable, you know.
What am I going to give him now?
Oh, right.
I have this.
I'll have to look into it myself.
He's bound to notice, though.
Mr. Stark.
Is he out?
A warrior carrying an axe?
He helped me push my cart.
I think he was headed toward the plaza.
He was playing with us until a moment ago.
He helped us out of that tree.
He stopped my rampaging cow.
He's been helping lots of people.
How could Ms. Frieren be so rude?
There's no way Mr. Stark would
appreciate that dirty potion.
Mr. Stark.
Whoa!
That cloud looks like boobs.
He's a perv after all.
For real? That one looks like a turd.
No, he's just a child.
I'll have to tell Fern about them later.
How am I supposed to respond to that?
Mr. Stark.
Fern, good timing. Those clouds...
Actually, sorry. It's nothing.
Uh, so...
Would you like to go for a walk?
Yes.
Hey, why are you mad? Did I do something?
How do I broach the subject?
Come on. I'll apologize, okay?
No matter how I ask,
he'll know something's up.
Then I'll just come out and say it.
Mr. Stark, is there anything you want?
What for?
It's your birthday today.
Is that right?
What's that got to do with what I want?
I'd like to get you a birthday present.
What? You're gonna give me something?
Actually, never mind.
You're kind of irritating.
Wait. I wasn't joking.
I've never received a birthday present before.
I never got one from my
dead family or my master,
so I just thought that was how it was.
Not even from your family?
Was it not the custom there?
No, they probably just didn't
care about me that much.
I'm originally from a village of warriors.
There was no place there for the weak.
That was a pathetic display
in front of that monster.
Try to be more like Stoltz.
Not only is he uninjured, but he doesn't
have a speck of blood or dirt on him.
His pure white cape proves he's
the strongest warrior in the village.
Stoltz, you're the pride of the village.
Of course, Dad.
But by contrast, Stark is a failure.
Despite training so hard every day,
he still hasn't faced down a monster.
It's starting to rain. Let's head home.
I'm going to train my
foolish younger brother.
Don't be too mean to him.
I'm heading home. You're wasting your time.
Stark.
Brother.
Sorry.
Good focus.
I know you'll become stronger, but your
stance could use some improvement.
Come to think of it, my brother
might've been different.
But...
When my village was attacked by monsters,
I abandoned even my brother and fled.
Maybe I shouldn't be surprised my family
never celebrated my birthday.
I was a failure who ran from everything.
I bet Himmel wouldn't have run.
Mr. Stark, let's go pick out a present.
The past doesn't matter.
The warrior Stark I've known has never run.
But I might in the future.
We won't let you.
But I—
If you won't choose, then I'm
choosing something for you.
Fine.
I'd like this, then.
No. That's expensive.
Okay.
Welcome back. You're late.
Ms. Frieren, what are those
ridiculously large hamburg steaks?
What are you talking about?
This is how you celebrate a birthday.
My master never gave me any gifts,
but he did make me birthday hamburg steaks.
What do you mean?
Stark, Eisen didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Warriors are so awkward.
You're one to talk, aren't you, Ms. Frieren?
You're right. I understand
because I'm awkward, too.
It's foolish, isn't it?
People won't know how you feel
unless you tell them.
This is...
Come to think of it,
you always make ridiculously large
hamburg steaks on our birthdays.
What's that about?
It's a custom in my region.
They're a gift to honor warriors
who have worked hard.
It's like a birthday present from me.
But Eisen, we're not warriors.
Everyone who works hard is a warrior.
Really?
Who can say?
Warriors who have worked hard...
Brother, what are you making?
Hamburg steak. It's your birthday, isn't it?
Don't tell the rest of the family.
Run, Stark.
You have to live.
Eisen gave me the recipe.
Is it good?
Yeah.
I have some of this left over, too.
I'll pour it over your
head again, Ms. Frieren.
Huh? What's that?
None of your business.
A valuable potion.
What? What's it do?
Perv.
What? How am I a perv?
Seriously, why?
And you alright
Can you hear me
Trailing along deserted train tracks
Crying excessively
Wanting you to smile
I hold on to memories I'd like to keep fresh
There's something I'd like to tell you
With words more precious than a goodbye
Unremarkable yet special
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
So, if I were to be born again
I would surely choose this place once more
So, if we were to meet again
I'd never let you go, I'd choose the present
Even if no promises were made
Even if I'm lost in days of loneliness
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
Himmel!
My nose is starting to bleed.
You're a wicked woman.
Alcohol is the best medicine.
So what, Frieren?
Too much time has passed.
Nothing that can be done now.
Grown-ups are dirty.
He also likes older women.
It's an aversion to my own kind, I guess.